OWULEZI OSINACHI SAMUEL

Home: 51 Irepodun Street, Ijeshatedo, Surulere, Lagos State

Telephone: +2348130544890

E-mail: samuel_owulezi@yahoo.com

Born: 16th May 1989

State: Isiala Mbano LGA, Imo state

SUMMARY:

Higly motivated self-taught web developer with a sound knowledge of JavaScript, React Js, Node js, Python, Django framework, SQL and NoSQL (MongoDB) programming languages. To contribute to the development of a highly competitive product, improving user experience, and enhancing both personal and organizational growth.

SKILLS HIGHLIGHT:

- Sound analytical thinking
- Writing clean and concise codes, frontend and backend
- Querying database, SQL and NoSQL
- Ability to understand codes written by other developers
- Knowledge of databases and operating systems
- Ability to learn on the fly

WEB PROJECTS:

Personal projects and related codes can be viewed via my GitHub page and my portfolio

Portfolio URL: https://scottsam.github.io/my-portfolio/

GitHub URL: https://www.github.com/scottsam

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Software Developer trainee, Omela Solutions, Surulere, Lagos State. (September 2019 – January 2020)

- Worked with a team of experienced web developer to build an online market place for merchants and customers
- Designed and implement frontend interfaces and backend services to assemble web applications based on user stories.
- Built functional interfaces for mobile-first, dynamic web applications.
- Product testing under development
- Identified and reported bugs in the application

IT Support, High-Tech Data Systems Limited(HDS), Lagos State. (January 2017 – March 2019)

- Provided client support and technical issue resolution via email, phone and other electronic mediums.
- Provided training to clients in the use of systems and applications.
- Hardware and software configuration as needed.
- Hardware and software troubleshooting.
- Technical documentation and training of End Users

National Youth Service Corps (NYSC), Bright learners College, Akure, Ondo state. (August 2014 – August 2015)

- Mathematics and Physics Teacher,
- Prepared Students for GCE, WAEC, UTME and Post-UTME.
- Provided home support when required.

EDUCATION:

| SCHOOL | COURSE/QUALIFICATION | YEAR OBTAINED |
|---|---|---------------|
| Federal University of Technology Owerri Imo State. | Chemical Engineering B.Eng. | 2013 |
| Ijeshatedo Boys Secondary School, Sanya Surulere Lagos. | Senior School Certificate Examination [SSCE]. | 2004 |
| Innocent Childeren international nursery and Primary School, Lagos. | First leaving School Certificate. | 1998 |

INTEREST

- Learning and Writing Codes
- Reading and Researching
- Soccer
- Cooking

REFEREES

Available on request.